Once we have sealed one end of the rain stick were ready to pour our rice inside and close off the other end.
The easiest way to do this is to put your rice into a plastic bag and then just put the mouth of the paper bag inside of the paper towel roll and tilt the bag over so all the rice will spill right inside.
If you don't do it this way then you can use some type of funnel or something where the mouth fits inside the end of the rain stick and you can just pour the rice right inside.
But this is easiest way.
So once all the rice is inside were going to go ahead and seal the top of the stick.
We put the other lid the other circle that we cut out over the top and we do the same thing it should fit right on it shouldn't slip inside because of the thickness of the roll will help keep it on.
Just sitting on the outside and then we go ahead and take some masking tape and put it around the outside of the lid.
Around the roll and that helps create a seal.
We should put a few layers just like we did before and again this is going to help prevent any of the rice from falling out.
It creates a nice tight seal and really want to make sure that that lid stays place.
So we go ahead and put it around and fold the excess right over the top and once we have gone around and we feel that its in place then we can go ahead and put some tape right along the bottom.
So now our rain stick has been totally sealed we have the rice inside and as we move it back and forth we'll see that it going to, its going to sound like the rain falling.
Hitting a window.
Hitting a roof or just falling outside.
So now I shown you how to place the rice inside our rain stick and seal the end with the lid and masking tape.